Welcome! In the last lecture, we created this project for us to work with using third-person
欢迎大家 在上次讲座中，我们创建了这个项目，让我们使用第三人称的
template. And before we move on, there's one more thing that I'd like to set up inside
模板。在我们继续之前，我还想在C++中设置一个东西，以使我们的生活更容易。
of C++ in order to make our lives much easier. So first, I'm going to close my project and
以使我们的生活更轻松。所以，首先，我要关闭我的项目，回到我的Visual Studio。
go back to my Visual Studio, giving you all the things that we want to do later, all the
回到我的Visual Studio，给你所有我们以后要做的事情，所有我们需要的
math operations that we need. It'll be much easier for us to accomplish them if we have
我们需要的数学运算。如果我们有一个调试助手，我们就能更容易地完成这些操作。
a debug helper. Quite frequently, we'll need to print something either to the screen or
一个调试助手。很多时候，我们需要打印一些东西到屏幕上或
to the log, so having a handy debug function can really speed up this process. So first,
到日志中，所以有一个方便的调试函数可以真正加快这个过程。所以，首先、
I'm going to go to this Climbing System folder, right mouse button click, and I'm going to
我将进入这个 "攀登系统 "文件夹，点击鼠标右键，然后我将会
click Add and select New Item. So I like to put the debug functionality inside of a single
点击添加并选择新项目。所以我喜欢把调试功能放在一个单一的
header file. So I'm going to select this header file and I'm going to rename this file to
头文件中。所以我将选择这个头文件，并将这个文件重命名为
Debug Helper. Then inside of this location, we'll need to manually change it to our source
Debug Helper。然后在这个位置，我们需要手动把它改成我们的源代码
folder. So I'm going to click this Browse, go back to this Climbing System folder, and
文件夹。所以我将点击这个浏览，回到这个攀登系统文件夹，然后
go to Source, double click to open this Climbing System and click Select Folder. And later,
转到源文件，双击打开这个攀登系统，然后点击选择文件夹。而后、
we should be able to save this file under our source folder. All right, I'm going to
我们应该能够把这个文件保存在我们的源文件夹下。好的，我将会
click Add. And first thing, I'm going to first include this file inside of my Character class.
点击添加。首先，我要把这个文件包含在我的角色类中。
By doing this, we should be able to have the auto completion back inside of that file.
通过这样做，我们应该能够在该文件中重新获得自动完成功能。
So inside of this Character.h, I'm going to press Ctrl+K and Ctrl+O to go to its Cpp
所以在Character.h里面，我将按Ctrl+K和Ctrl+O转到其Cpp
file. Then I'm going to type in pal include and the file that I want to include is this
文件。然后我将输入pal include，我想包含的文件是这个
Debug Helper.h. All right, after that, I'm going to press Ctrl+B to compile. All right,
Debug Helper.h。好的，在这之后，我将按Ctrl+B进行编译。好的、
I have a successful compile and I'm going to go back to this Debug Helper.h. So first,
我有一个成功的编译，我将回到这个Debug Helper.h。那么首先、
I'm going to type in namespace and I'm going to call this namespace Debug. This is just
我将键入命名空间，我将把这个命名空间称为Debug。这只是
to prevent any possible naming conflicts that we might have in the future. All right, then
以防止我们将来可能出现的任何命名冲突。好的，然后
follow by open braces. The function that I'm going to create, you'll be a static function
后面是大括号。我要创建的这个函数，将是一个静态函数
and you'll be void. I'm going to call it print. It's going to have a few input parameters.
并且是无效的。我将把它称为打印。它将会有几个输入参数。
So the first one, you'll be a const f string reference. I'm going to call this message.
所以第一个，你将是一个const f字符串的引用。我将把这个称为消息。
So this will be the message that we'll see on the screen later. And next, you'll be a
所以这将是我们以后在屏幕上看到的信息。接下来，你将得到一个
const f color, also going to be a reference. I'm going to call this color and I'm going
const f颜色，也是一个引用。我将调用这个颜色，并且我将给它一个默认值。
to give it a default value. So you'll be f color, double colon. I'm going to type in make
给它一个默认值。所以你将是f color，双冒号。我将输入使
random color. Later, if we need to print our message every frame, we do need to specify
随机颜色。以后，如果我们需要每一帧都打印我们的信息，我们确实需要在这里手动指定
the color manually in here. Otherwise, this make random color will just work. And the
在这里手动指定颜色。否则，这个make random color就可以工作了。而
last input, you'll be an int 32. I'm going to call this int key. So this will be the key
最后一个输入，你将是一个int 32。我将把这个称为int key。所以这将是我们显示信息的关键
for us to display the message. I'm going to give it a default value of negative one. A
用于显示信息。我将给它一个默认值，即负1。A
value of negative one will make sure when we're printing multiple messages, the newer message
负一的值将确保我们在打印多条信息时，较新的信息
will be on top. And later, if we want to print something every frame, we might also want
将被放在上面。以后，如果我们想每一帧都打印一些东西，我们可能还想
to specify the value for this parameter as well so that our screen won't have thousands
指定这个参数的值，这样我们的屏幕就不会有成千上万的
of messages. All right. Instead of this function, I'm first going to type if g engine, then
的信息。好的。我不使用这个函数，而是先输入if g引擎，然后
I'm going to use the function at on screen debug message. The first parameter that we
我将在屏幕上的调试信息处使用这个函数。我们的第一个参数
need to fill in is this key. Well, you'll be our inky and the time to display. I'm going
需要填写的第一个参数是这个键。好吧，你将是我们的墨迹和显示的时间。我打算
to give it a value of six seconds. And the display color is going to be our color and
给它一个6秒的值。显示的颜色将是我们的颜色，信息将是我们的信息。
the message is going to be our message. As simple as that. And after that, I'm also going
信息将是我们的信息。就这么简单。在这之后，我还将
to print this message to the log. So I'm going to use ue log and you'll be locked temp. I'm
来打印这个信息到日志中。所以我将使用ue log，你将被锁定temp。我将
going to type in warning and the message is going to be our input parameter. So I'm going
输入警告，信息将成为我们的输入参数。所以我将
to type in present as then followed by an asterisk and you'll be our message. All right. Just
输入 "目前"，后面加个星号，你就是我们的信息。好的。就这样
like that. Now let's test this. So go back to my character system dot cpp. I'm going
像这样。现在我们来测试一下。所以回到我的字符系统点cpp。我将会
to go down to this begin play under this line for add input mapping context. I'm going to
在这行下边开始播放添加输入映射的上下文。我将会
type in debug. So this is our namespace double column and we can access the function print
键入debug。所以这是我们的命名空间双列，我们可以访问函数print
since we already mark this function a static function. We can include this file in different
因为我们已经把这个函数标记为静态函数。我们可以把这个文件包含在不同的
places without any linking errors. So the message that I'm going to print would be debug
我们可以在不同的地方包含这个文件，而不会出现任何链接错误。所以我要打印的信息将是debug
working and I'm going to press control plus at five to launch my editor. All right. Go
工作，我将在5点按下控制键，启动我的编辑器。好的。回到
back to my editor. I'm going to click play and you can see we already have the message
回到我的编辑器。我将点击播放，你可以看到我们已经把信息
printing to the screen. And if I go to my output log we can already see a message in
打印到了屏幕上。如果我去看我的输出日志，我们已经可以在这里看到一条消息。
here and this is going to save us so much time later and it's time for you to do the
这将为我们以后节省很多时间，现在是时候让你也这样做了。
same. So the challenge is same as I did. I like you to create a header file for debugging.
是时候让你做同样的事情了。所以挑战和我一样。我希望你能创建一个头文件用于调试。
After that try printing something to screen to prove your debug helper is working. Feel
之后，试着在屏幕上打印一些东西，以证明你的调试助手在工作。感觉
free to refer back to the video if you need any help. All right. Pause the video now and
如果你需要任何帮助，可以参考视频。好了。现在暂停视频并
keep this a go and I'll see you in the next lecture.
保持这个状态，我们在下一节课见。
[Music]
[音乐]